The hierarchy of power in the DC Universe is about to change.
Black Adam is a action, adventure, science fiction
film directed by Jaume Collet-Serra.
Nearly 5,000 years after he was bestowed with the almighty powers of the Egyptian gods—and imprisoned just as
quickly—Black Adam is freed from his earthly tomb, ready to unleash his unique form of justice on the modern world.
Black Adam / Teth Adam, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Hawkman / Carter Hall, played by Aldis Hodge.
Atom Smasher / Al Rothstein, played by Noah Centineo.
Adrianna Tomaz, played by Sarah Shahi.
Cyclone / Maxine Hunkel, played by Quintessa Swindell.
Ishmael / Sabbac / King Ahk-Ton, played by Marwan Kenzari.
Black Adam is a 2022 American superhero film starring
Dwayne Johnson as the titular character.
Based on the DC character Teth-Adam / Black Adam,
the film is a spin-off from Shazam!
(2019) and the eleventh film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
Directed by Jaume Collet-Serra from a screenplay by Adam Sztykiel, Rory Haines and Sohrab Noshirvani, the film follows Teth-Adam / Black Adam, an ancient superhuman who is released from his magic imprisonment by
a group of archeologists to free the nation of Kahndaq from the crime syndicate Intergang, whose local leader plans to obtain an ancient relic called the Crown of Sabbac to take control of it.
Aldis Hodge, Noah Centineo, Sarah Shahi, Quintessa Swindell, Marwan
Kenzari and Pierce Brosnan appear in supporting roles.
Johnson was attached to Shazam!
early in development and confirmed to portray the villain Black Adam in September 2014, but the
producers, at Johnson's urging, later decided to give the character his own film.
Sztykiel was hired in October 2017.
Collet-Serra joined in June 2019 with a planned release date of December
2021, but this timeline was delayed by the COVID-19 pandemic.
Additional casting took place over the next year, including four members of the Justice
Society of America, along with the script being rewritten by Haines and Noshirvani.
Principal photography took place from April to August 2021 at Trilith
Studios in Atlanta, Georgia, and also in Los Angeles.
Black Adam premiered in Mexico City on October 3, 2022, and was
theatrically released in the United States on October 21.
It received mixed-to-negative reviews from critics and failed to break-even at the box
office, grossing $393 million worldwide against a budget of $190–$260 million.
The film explores themes of lightning, superhero,
anti hero, based on comic, demon.
The tone is thought_provoking.